Guide to the Culver Family Papers, 1858-1915
Department of Special Collections
Culver Family Papers,
1858-1915
Special Collections M0633
Culver family.
7.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Gloria R. Brown and the Palo Alto Historical Association, 1992, and Phyllis F. Dorset, 1996.
Biography
John Oscar Culver, born May 2, 1830, was one of ten children born to tailor James Culver and Kezia [Lee] Culver of Sandy Hill, New York (now Hudson's Falls). James Culver's grandfather, resident in New York and Connecticut, had fought for the Colonies in the Revolutionary War. All of James and Kezia Culver's children attended the local schools, and some went beyond grade school; most of them engaged in either commerce, banking, or government service in later life.
John Oscar Culver graduated from the Albany (NY) Law School in 1857, after having worked for several years in Troy, NY. On graduation, Oscar joined fellow classmates in the practice of law in Wisconsin. In 1860, he was appointed Assistant Attorney General for the state of Wisconsin, serving under James H. Howe. Coincident with his appointment, Oscar met and married (May 2, 1860) Minerva ("Minnie") Bliss, aged 22, a teacher, and daughter of farmer-businessman, Zebina Bliss, of Burlington, Wisconsin.
Soon after the outbreak of the Civil War, Oscar received an appointment as Additional Paymaster in the U.S. Army (August 1861), with the rank of Major. He was posted to the Pay Department, Headquarters, Department of the Northwest, at St. Louis, Missouri. From St. Louis, Oscar journeyed forth at quarterly intervals for weeks at a time paying troops in the field throughout southern Missouri and northeastern Arkansas, and down the Mississippi River during the campaign for Vicksburg, Mississippi, in 1863. In mid-1864, Oscar was transferred to Milwaukee, Wisconsin, to pay troops being mustered out of the Army; he served there until November 1865, when he resigned from the service.
For the first two years of the War, Minnie Culver and their first son, William, remained with relatives in Wisconsin and Illinois, with infrequent visits to St. Louis. In the last years of the War, Minnie and Will lived on a farm Oscar purchased outside Burlington, WI. Only seldom could Oscar get leave to go home to his family.
After the Civil War, Oscar served in the solicitor's office of the Chicago, North Western Railway, commuting from Chicago on a weekly basis to the home Minnie and he had established with their now three children (William, Paul, and Julia Louise) in Wawautosa, WI. In 1870, Oscar joined as partner and editor, with David C. Atwood, publisher of the Wisconsin State Journal in Madison, WI. He also engaged in diverse business ventures, including paper milling, strawberry cultivation, and iron mining, and was active in state politics and the Wisconsin Historical Society (curator). The Culver's last two children (George and Richard) were born in Madison. During this period, the family enjoyed a prominent position in the cultural and political life of Wisconsin's capital city.
In 1877, the Culvers moved to California, where Oscar became editor of the Alameda (California) Daily Times, with a residence in Oakland, CA. Oscar also purchased homesteads in the Napa Valley of California, and pursued acquisition and operation of gold mines in various parts of the state. In 1879, Culver began a new career as U.S. Postal Inspector, stationed first in San Francisco and later in southern California. In this capacity he traveled from town to town observing post office operations and receiving and investigating the complaints of postmasters and patrons to be adjudicated by his office. He retired from this occupation in 1902.
During Oscar's several careers, during which he was obligated to be away from home for long periods, Minnie reared their children and managed their several households. In their years of separation Minnie became an accomplished painter, and Oscar turned to writing, his short stories appearing in the Atlantic, Scribner's, and Harper's.
Two years after Stanford University opened in October 1891, the Culvers moved to Palo Alto, California, built a home, and sent four of their children to the University. Minnie and Oscar were also active in the city of Palo Alto, becoming founding members of the Congregational Church, along with making other contributions to civic life. In addition, they took into their home two foster children, both of whom died in childhood. John Oscar Culver died in 1912, and Minnie in 1916.
When the family moved to Palo Alto, Will Culver remained in Oakland with his wife, Margaret [Day], and daughter, Kathryn, commuting to business in San Francisco. Paul Culver, a student at Stanford from 1894-1896, married Nina Briggs in 1896, and had one child, Esther Miriam Culver. Paul served as Palo Alto City Attorney, and also managed for a time the Culver family orchard in Lindsay, CA. After the death of his wife, Paul returned to Palo Alto, married Mrs. Sally Waldorf, and operated a jewelry store in Palo Alto until his death in 1931. Julia Louise, known as Lulu, graduated in English from Stanford in 1896, taught high school, married and divorced Walter N. Brown, lost a child in childbirth, became a published poet, and throughout her life maintained ties to campus life; she died in 1959. George Culver received his degree from Stanford in Zoology in 1897, took a position with the Smithsonian Institution in Washington, D.C., received a law degree from George Washington University, and ultimately returned to California. He became a teacher and a city administrator in southern California, then Dean of Men at Stanford University from 1920 to 1938, and was emeritus until his death in 1949. George and his wife, Sabina [Burks], adopted a son, George Jr., who was killed in World War II. George's twin brother, Richard Culver, graduated from Stanford University in 1899, becoming in his student years an illustrator for The Quad, the campus magazine. Richard went on to become a newspaper cartoonist in Baltimore, Maryland, until his death in 1939.
Kathryn Culver, who attended Stanford from 1906-1908, married the Rev. Dwight Bradley in Palo Alto in 1914, and was living in Carmel, CA, at the time of her Aunt Lulu's death in 1959. Esther Culver also attended Stanford, from 1919-1920, and resided in Berkeley at the time of her Aunt Lulu's death.
The California Culver family kept in close contact with their relatives and friends in the East as well as with those who had also come to California. Consequently, there is a strong continuity in their relationships with their extended family (and friends) throughout the period covered by their collected papers, 1858-1915.
Scope and Content
The Culver Family Papers collection consists of fourteen boxes (7.5 linear ft.) of letters to and from family members, friends, and acquaintances, as well as manuscripts, journals, and miscellaneous papers. The collection covers the years 1858 to 1915, with the material in the 1860s predominating. Missing, however, are letters from Minnie Bliss Culver to John Oscar Culver for 1865, and from John Oscar Culver to Minnie Culver for 1869. There are also gaps in the correspondence from Minnie to Oscar for 1891, 1894-1896. The decades with fewest letters are the 1870s and 1900s.
A guide to the individual boxes and folders contains the number of letters in each folder and key names, places, and events treated. An index by date, addressee, sender, and point of origin is also included. Some of the letters are faded and barely legible; for these, photocopies accompany the originals. Also, some letters and papers are written on legal-sized paper. These have been removed to oversized (OS) boxes, and the location of these documents is referenced in the appropriate folders in the guide to individual boxes.
The Collection reflects J. O. Culver's experience as a lawyer, his service as an Army Paymaster and Post Office Inspector, his endeavors in small fruit culture, and his excursions into prospecting and mining. As a result of these activities, much of his life was spent away from home, with consequent hardship. However, the Collection is also testimony to the fortitude of Minnie Culver in rearing their five children and keeping the family unit whole under trying circumstances.
In general, the family letters and papers give a panorama of middle class society in New York, Wisconsin and Missouri, and Colorado and California, from 1860 to 1915, a familiar pattern in the United States of looking ever westward for opportunity.
Access Terms
Culver, George Bliss, d.1949.; Culver, John Oscar, d.1912.; Culver, Louise Julia, d.1959.; Culver, Minnie Bliss, d.1916.; Culver, Paul Drury, d.1931.; Culver, Richard Keith, d.1939.; Culver, William Lee, d.1920.; Palo Alto (Calif.)--History.; Stanford University--History--19th century.
Container List
- Family History/Geneology & Family Correspondence, 1860s.
  - Geneology & Family History, Culver & Bliss Families., (12 documents) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    See also, Box 7, F32, for letter to Oscar Culver fm George Culver; Box 7, F35 to Minnie Culver fm Louise Culver, Jul 8, 1905; Box 7, F40 to Will Culver fm Oscar & Minnie Culver, Jul 1, 1903; Box 12, F1, J. O. Culver application to Sons of the Revolution [1895?]; Box 12, F12, to Oscar Culver fm Richard Culver, Mar 21, 1901.
  - Letters to Minnie Culver from John Oscar Culver, 1860., (9 letters) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    [William Henry] Seward, BGen George H. Nye, U.S.A. Charles Francis Adams. Mrs. [Governor] Lewis P. Harvey [Wisconsin].
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1861 (Jun-Oct)., (12 letters) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    See also, Box 12, F2, for letter to Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, Oct 1, 1861, & Oct 9, 1861. Paymaster appointment requirements. Hannibal, Mo. BGen Benjamin Prentiss, U.S.A., and rebel activity, eastern Missouri. Views on women. "Wisconsin money."
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1861 (Nov-Dec)., (9 letters) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Views on literature & letter writing. Wisconsin election results, 1861. James Colton [U.S. Congressman, Wisconsin].
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1862 (Jan-Jun)., (9 letters) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    See also, Box 12, F2 for letter of Mar 23, 1862. Steamboating on the Mississippi River. Steamer George Washington Graham. 17th Reg't. Illinois Volunteer Cavalry, U.S.A., 2nd Reg't. Wisconsin Volunteer Cavalry, U.S.A. Jeff (& Mrs.) Thompson [Confederate raider]. Rebel marauders in S.W. Missouri. Trent question and Abraham Lincoln [anec.]. Views on Civil War. Evaluation of Confederate morale. Cavalry night scouting parties.
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1862 (Jul-Dec)., (9 letters) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    U.S. Army reaction to defeat in front of Richmond, VA. Bushwhacker activity, S.W. Missouri. U.S. Army force concentration, under BGen John M. Schofield. St. Louis patriotic fervor. 20th Reg't. Wisconsin Volunteer Cavalry.
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1863 (Jan-Jun)., (12 letters) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    T[imothy] O. Howe [U.S. Senator, Wis.]. Louis M. Gottschalk. Mrs. [MGen] Francis J. Herron, U.S.A. Typhoid and smallpox, St. Louis. Forsyth, Missouri. U.S. Army of the Frontier. Bolan, "Outlaw of the Ozarks." 1st Reg't. Iowa Volunteer Cavalry, 12th Reg't. Iowa Volunteer Cavalry. Camp Bliss [Mo?]. Troop transport on the Mississippi River, steamers Planet, Henry Clay, Hiawatha. Mrs. [MGen] Jeff Thompson. Milliken's Bend, Young's Point, canal strategy on the Mississippi. 14th Division, 13th Army Corps, U.S.A.
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1863 (Jul-Aug)., (9 letters) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Seven Sisters [drama]. St. Louis, Missouri, in the Civil War. New York draft riots. U.S.A. Paymaster functions and mode of travel. Conscription of U.S.A. Paymaster clerks. 2nd Reg't. Wisconsin Volunteer Cavalry.
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1863 (Sep-Dec)., (16 letters) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    See also, Box 12, F2, for letter to Minnie Culver fm Oscar Culver, Sep 19, 1863. Danger faced by U.S. Army Paymasters. Bushwhackers operating in Missouri: Jim Lane, Hunter, Quantrell, Norris, Coffee. Opinions on U.S. Army. BGen John McNeil, U.S.A. 1st Arkansas Reg't. Volunteer Cavalry, U.S.A. Shelby's raid [C.S.A.], Arkansas and Missouri. Rev. Henry Giles. Strawberry & blackberry culture.
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1864 (Jan-Feb)., (9 letters) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Conflagration, Chile, 1864. Steamer John H. Dickey.
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1864 (Mar-May)., (10 letters) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    See also, Box 12, F2 for letter to Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, May 20, 1864. Col. Nathan W. Brown, Deputy Paymaster General. St. Louis Exhibition, April 1864. Small fruit cultivation.
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1864 (Jun-Dec)., (11 letters) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    2nd Reg't. Wisconsin Volunteer Infantry. James H. Howe [Attorney General, Wisconsin]. 9th Reg't. Wisconsin Volunteer Infantry. Lincoln, as model for president. Small fruit cultivation. Paper manufacture.
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1865., (7 letters) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Paymaster salary. Governor Lewis P. Harvey (Wisconsin). Horace Rublee [Publisher]. Oil speculation and swindling.
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1866-1868., (31 letters) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    See also, Box 12, F2 for letter to Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, Oct 22, 1866. Prince Albert potatoes. Burlington [Wis.] brick. James H. Howe. Chicago & North Western Railway. Strawberry culture.
  - To Will L. Culver from Oscar Culver, 1867., (2 letters) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    [?] Anthony, illustrator, Young Folks magazine (NY). W.A. Wakeman [U.S. Congressman, New York].
- Correspondence, Family & Friends, 1850s-1860s.
  - To Oscar Culver from Minnie Culver, 1861-1862., (15 letters) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    LCol. [Oscar H.] LaGrange [1st Reg't. Wisconsin Volunteer Cavalry]. Harper's Weekly. Fremont Body Guard. 24th Reg't. Missouri State Militia. 2nd Reg't. Wisconsin Volunteer Infantry. Governor and Mrs. Lewis P. Harvey.
  - To Oscar Culver from Minnie Culver, 1863., (18 letters) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    BGen John C. Starkweather U.S.A. Wartime St. Louis, inflation, smallpox. Antietam. Col. Hans Hegg. T. O. Howe [U.S. Senator].
  - To Oscar Culver from Minnie Culver, 1864., (24 letters) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    BGen Egbert B. Brown [7th Reg't. Missouri Volunteer Infantry]. Farming procedures.
  - To Oscar Culver from Minnie Culver, 1866-1869., (30 letters) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Kenosha, Wauwatosa, Wisconsin.
  - To Oscar & Minnie from James & Kezia Culver, 1860s., (1 letter) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - To Oscar Culver from Louis B. and Kate N. Lee, 1859., (2 letters) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - To/from Oscar/Minnie Culver & Cyrus L. Culver, 1860s., (6 letters) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Cattle buying.
  - To Oscar Culver from Charles D. Culver, 1858-1862., (20 letters) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    W. A. Wakeman (U.S. Congressman). Civil War sutlers and commission agents. U.S.S. Trent, U.S.S. Nashville, wartime WDC. Draft of 1862. 53rd Reg't. New York Volunteer Infantry, Pierpont Rifles Brigade.
  - To Oscar Culver from Charles D. Culver 1863-1869., (18 letters) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Wall Street. Oil Market. Civil War veterans, regular army [U.S.A.], and political appointments.
  - To Oscar Culver from James L. Culver, 1860s., (13 letters) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Paper mill operation. See also, Box 3, F24 for additional letters on paper mill activities.
  - To Oscar from George B. Culver 1858-1863., (10 letters) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    J. A. Bently [Judge, Wis.]. Civil War Army enlistment (Wis.).
  - To Oscar from George B. Culver, 1864-1868., (13 letters) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Civil War Union Army sutlers and paymasters.
  - To/from Oscar Culver & Mary Eliza [Richards], 1860s., (4 letters) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Views on religion.
  - To/from Oscar Culver & Thomas L. Culver, 1860s., (8 letters) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - To Oscar & Thomas Culver from Stephen Culver, 1860s., (2 letters) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    W. A. Wakeman (U.S. Congressman).
  - To Oscar/Minnie Culver from Nephew Charles M. Culver, 1860s., (2 letters) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - To/from Charles Culver and James Culver, 1860s., (4 letters) (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Sketch of Civil War battle plan.
  - To Cyrus Culver from Charles D. Culver, 1860s., (2 letters) (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Pacific R.R. and Iowa land.
  - To/from Oscar Culver and Julia Bliss, 1860s., (4 letters) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - To Oscar Culver from [?] [?] Barnes, 1860s., (2 letters) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - To Oscar Culver from Charles W. Bennett, 1859-1861., (19 letters) (Box 2, Folder 21)
    See also, Box 12, F4 for additional letters to the Culvers from the Bennetts. Republican politics (Wis.). Burlington (Wis.) school board.
  - To Oscar Culver from Charles W. Bennett, 1862-1868., (14 letters) (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Racine County politics (Wis.). Wisconsin Advocate. James H. Howe [Attorney General, Wis.]. See also, Box 12, F4 for additional letters to the Culvers from the Bennetts.
  - To Oscar Culver from J. A. Bently, 1850s-1860s., (3 letters) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - To Oscar Culver from S. P. Billings, 1859-1861., (2 letters) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - To Oscar Culver from W. P. Britten, 1860s., (2 letters) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Eau Clair [Wis.] Badgers.
  - To Oscar Culver from A. J. Cole, 1859., (2 letters) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - To/from Oscar Culver & DeWitt C. Conkey, 1860s., (8 letters) (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Burlington [WI].
  - To Oscar Culver from Amos Dean, 1850s., (2 letters) (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Albany [NY] Law School.
  - To Oscar Culver from John B. Eugene, 1860s., (4 letters) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Wisconsin politics, 1861. Hans Hegg. [Governor Lewis P.] Harvey. Samuel Hastings. Jermain Soloman. Belgian Settlement [Wis.]. 8th, 10th, and 11th Reg'ts. Missouri Volunteer Infantry.
  - To Oscar Culver from Belle Finlayson, 1860s., (2 letters) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - To Oscar Culver from George Gibson, 1850s-1860s., (15 letters) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    See also Box 12, F8 for letter to Oscar Culver from George Gibson [Dec?] 19, 1862 & Sep 24, 1864. James H. Howe. New York politics, 1860s. Civil War: Army of Kentucky, 16th Reg't. New York Volunteer Infantry. MGen A. J. Smith. Camp Bates, KY.
  - To Oscar Culver from George B. Goodwin, 1860s., (3 letters) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    See also, Box 12, F8 for letter to Oscar Culver from George Goodwin, Apr 25, 1860. James H. Howe.
  - To Oscar Culver from John C. Greene, 1860s., (4 letters) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - To Oscar Culver from A. W. Hammond, 1860s., (10 letters) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    See also, Box 12, F8 for letter to Oscar Culver fm A. W. Hammond, Oct. 23, 1865. Civil War garrison duty. Craft of fiction,. Kenosha Telegraph.
  - To Oscar Culver from James H. Howe (& wife), 1860s., (15 letters) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Wisconsin politics, 1860s. Governor Lewis P. Harvey [Wis.]
  - To Oscar Culver from Timothy O. Howe, 1860s., (5 letters) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Fugitive Slave Act, 1859. General Benjamin F. Larned [Paymaster General].
  - To/from Oscar Culver and [LCol] O. H. LaGrange, 1860., (2 letters) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Booth rescue. U.S. Statute Ch. 9, Sec. 32 (1790).
  - To Oscar Culver from John J. McClellan, 1850s-1860s., (18 letters) (Box 3, Folder 16)
    James H. Howe. Oconto, Wis. Wisconsin politics. Conditions in Missouri, Civil War. U.S. Army Paymaster appointees.
  - To Oscar Culver from William H. Norris, Jr., 1860., (2 letters) (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Wisconsin currency. [Governor] Lewis P. Harvey.
  - To/from Oscar Culver & [?] [?] Robinson, 1859., (2 letters) (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Green Bay Advocate.
  - To Oscar Culver from James S. Rogers, 1860s., (8 letters) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Charles W. Bennett. Edward Dyer, M.D. Burlington, Wis. politics. Small fruit culture.
  - To Oscar Culver from Horace Rublee, 1860s., (5 letters) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Wisconsin State Journal, Emigranten [newspaper, Wis.], C. F. Solberg. See also Box 12, F5, 6, 7: Letters to Oscar & Minnie Culver from George & Mary E. [Luella] Westover, 1859-1866.
  - To Oscar Culver from James M. Wilson, 1860s., (12 letters) (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Missouri politics. Pay Department, U.S. Army. Service magazine. Frank P. Blair, [Postmaster General]. T. O. Howe (U.S. Senator). James Doolittle (U.S. Senator). Andrew Jackson impeachment.
  - To/from Oscar Culver as Asst. Attorney General [Wisconsin], 1860-1861., (10 letters) (Box 3, Folder 22)
    [Governor Alexander W. Randall, Wis.]. James H. Howe. Louis P. Harvey. Wisconsin politics. Orasmus Cole. State School Fund [Wisconsin].
  - To/from Oscar Culver on Paymaster Matters, 1861-1867., (20 letters) (Box 3, Folder 23)
    See also, Box 13, F3 for additional letters & papers on paymaster matters. U.S. Army pay procedures. Benjamin F. Larned, Paymaster General. Paymasters, post-Civil War. Frank P. Blair [Postmaster General]. T. O. Howe (U.S. Senator).
  - To Oscar Culver on Paper Mill Matters, 1864-1865., (5 letters) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - To Oscar Culver Regarding Badger Oil Co., 1865., (2 letters & 3 stock certificate receipts) (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - To/from Oscar Culver as Attorney for Chicago North Western Railway, 1867-1869., (6 letters) (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Silas B. A. Haynes [U.S. Congressman]. Nathan W. Brown. Judge P[erry] H. Smith.
  - To/from Oscar Culver & Literary Editors, 1866-1869., (16 letters) (Box 3, Folder 27)
    "Robbed of Half a Million." "The Plaintiff Unsuited." "Van Rushing's Will." Atlantic Monthly. Harper's Weekly. G. P. Putnam & Co.
  - To/from Oscar Culver & Misc., 1859-1864., (18 letters) (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Rufus King. Milwaukee Sentinel. Wisconsin politics. Small fruit culture.
  - To/from Oscar Culver & Misc., 1865-1869., (19 letters) (Box 3, Folder 29)
    Silas B. A. Haynes [U.S. Congressman].
- Correspondence & Miscellaneous Papers, Family and Friends, 1850s-1900s; n.d.
  - To/from Minnie & Oscar Culver and Zebina & Ellen S. Bliss, 1860s., (20 letters) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    See also Box 12, F3 for letter to Minnie Culver from Ellen S. Bliss & Julia Bliss, Jun 29, 1864.
  - To/from Minnie Culver & Julia Bliss, 1860s., (8 letters) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - To Minnie Culver from Edwin Bliss & Family, 1860s., (5 letters) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Civil War: Camp Walker, KY; life in a Union Army Camp; campaign for Atlanta, 1864. General John Bell Hood, CSA.
  - To Minnie & Oscar Culver from Timothy W. Bliss & Sam Powell, 1860s., (5 letters) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Civil War: Camp life outside Danville, KY; 92nd and 96th Reg'ts. Illinois Volunteer Infantry; naval service on Mississippi, Tennessee, & Cumberland Rivers.
  - To Minnie Culver from Nellie Bliss, 1860s., (6 letters) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - To/from Martha [Bliss] Chipman and Minnie Culver, 1860s., (2 letters) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - To Minnie Culver from Sara Saxe, 1850s-1860s., (4 letters) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - To Minnie Culver from Mary Lee, 1867., (1 letter) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - To/from Minnie Culver and Mary Eliza Richards, 1860s., (4 letters) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - To Minnie Culver from Charles D. & Louise Culver, 1860s., (3 letters) (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Painting technique. James Hart Earnest[?].
  - To Minnie Culver from George and James Culver, 1860s., (6 letters) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - To Minnie Culver from Thomas Culver, 1860s., (14 letters) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - To Minnie Culver from Stephen B. Culver, 1860s., (3 letters) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - To Minnie & Oscar Culver from Adile & Orra Akins, 1860s., (25 letters) (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Post Civil War South. Col. Timothy P. Andrews, Paymaster General, Col. Nathan W. Brown.
  - To Minnie Culver from Isobell Bennett [Mrs. Charles W.], 1860s., (18 letters) (Box 4, Folder 15)